The SCOAN Sunday Service
- Hallelujah.
- Amen.
Happy birthday.
Thank you. While you are sitting down,
you can say to the Lord,
“Lord Jesus, You are the Author of my faith.
Today, I need my faith to act.
Help my words and my thoughts”.
Bow down your heads, "I need my faith".
He is the Author of your faith.
You need your faith right now to act.
Help me – help my words and my thoughts.
You are the Author of my faith.
Lord Jesus, I need my faith now to act.
Help my words and my thoughts,
in Jesus Christ’s name.
Yes.
- Hallelujah.
- Amen.
Let’s take a look at the Book of Colossians, the Book of John, the Book of Acts and the Book of Ephesians.
We will take our first reading from the
Book of Colossians 3, verse 16.
“Let the message of Christ dwell among you richly…”
That is abundantly.
That is our proof text, but read
from the beginning of that Book.
“Since, then, you have been raised with Christ,
set your hearts on things above..."
Like I have told you, "Set your heart on things above".
"... where Christ is, seated at the right hand
of God.” - Colossians 3:1
Take a look at the verse 16,
“Let the message of Christ dwell among you richly
as you teach and admonish one another
with all wisdom through psalms, hymns,
and songs from the Spirit…” - Colossians 3:16
- Hallelujah.
- Amen.
The Book of Ephesians 3:17.
“so that Christ may dwell in your hearts through faith…”
It means through faith, Christ can dwell in your heart.
Christ dwells in my heart through faith.
Hallelujah.
Take your reading from the beginning.
I’m giving you the proof text.
Let's go to the Book of John 15, verse 7.
“If you remain in me and my words remain in you,
ask whatever you wish, and it will be done for you.”
When you take your time to read that
Book of Ephesians 3:17, and Colossians 3:16,
and the Book of Acts 20:32, you will agree
with me that Christ and the Word are One.
Jesus Christ and the Word are One.
The Book of John 15:7 says,
“If you dwell in Me and My Word dwells in
you, ask whatsoever and it shall be done”.
If Christ dwells in you and His
Word dwells in you; can you see?
Christ and the Word are One.
In Ephesians you will find the same; it says that
Christ can only live in you through faith,
live in your heart through faith.
Our heart is of faith.
Man’s heart is of faith, not man’s mind.
When you say "Heart", you mean your Spirit - Biblical.
In this way, it is the Word dominating us
that produces prayer fruits – that is, result.
You say, "In the name of Jesus..." - what are you saying?
Are you saying this with all your heart?
Because saying, "In the name of Jesus..."...
We know Christ through His Word.
We know Him through the Word.
"In the name of Jesus. In the blood of Jesus. In the name of Jesus...";
what are you saying?
Are you with all your heart, you mean it?
It is the Word dominating us that
produces the prayer fruit, result -
not the Word committed to memory
which is of course valuable in itself
but cannot produce prayer fruits.
But cannot do what?
It cannot produce prayer fruits.
How can the Word dwell in our hearts?
The Word dwells in our hearts when
we read it slowly, attentively and repeatedly
without holding grudges.
You say, "How will I read... ?"
If I hold grudges towards any
of my neighbors anywhere,
I should not be surprised that the Word is no longer real to me while talking, preaching, reading.
If the Word is no longer real to me, "In the name of Jesus" - I'm talking to myself; it is no real.
"Be healed!" - I'm talking of myself,
because it is no longer real.
So, in the same way you do.
If I hold grudges, I should not be surprised
to see that the Word is no longer real to me
when reading, preaching, talking, praying.
Can you see the challenges we are facing?
Committing the Word to memory is of course
valuable in itself but cannot produce prayer fruits;
they cannot produce result.
We know Christ through the Word.
Through the Word, we know Jesus Christ.
It is the Word that has taught
us the value of the name, Jesus,
the authority of the name and
our legal right to the use of the name.
It is the Word - the Word of God.
Our legal right to the use of the name.
Nobody will challenge you when you say,
"In the name of Jesus" - nobody will accuse you,
but the legal right to use the name by the
power of Holy Ghost - it is the Word that taught us.
How can the Word dwell in us?
The Word dwells in us when we read it
slowly, attentively and repeatedly
without holding grudges.
How many of us here are free
from grudges, pain of the past?
“Forgive us as we forgive those who sin against us.”
That is what the Bible is saying.
When you read the Bible, you hear from God.
“Forgive us as we forgive those who sin against us.”
Whether wrongly or rightly; in whatever way.
And you are carrying the Bible to read.
The Word dominating us is the Lordship of Christ in us.
A good example: “Be healed, in the name of Jesus!”
“In the name of Jesus, be delivered!”
“In the name of Jesus, be set free!”
It is the Word dominating us that
brings Jesus to the scene
and instantly, healing takes place.
It is the Word dwelling in us that
brings Jesus to the scene.
"Jesus!", and He will come.
It is the Word dominating us, dwelling in us,
living in us that brings Jesus to the scene.
Now, you know where your challenges come from.
Though, you have the Bible, the name
"Jesus" you know how to call,
but it seems that name is not giving the result.
Listen, we know Jesus Christ through the Word.
Without the Word is without Jesus Christ.
Has the Word ruled us?
Jesus is building Himself into us
and making Himself a part of us.
Tell your neighbour, “Is the Word dominating us?”
I mean, is the Word dwelling in us?
Is the Word living in us?
Is the Word ruling us?
Jesus is building Himself in us and
making Himself a part of us.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The more you meditate, the more
your spirit acts upon the Word
and the more the Word becomes part of you.
The more you meditate on what you read in the Bible,
the more your spirit acts upon the Word,
or you say the more your heart - it is the
same as your spirit acts upon the Word,
and the more the Word becomes part of you.
When the Word becomes part of you,
you can make use of it.
Then, you can say, “In the name of Jesus, be free!”
And if there is freedom, it means
that the Word has become part of you.
When the Word becomes part of you,
you can say, “Jesus!”
When you sleep and there is a nightmare or an attack in the dream, some people come to attack you,
you say, "Jesus!" and you see them bow,
instead of when you see people in the dream,
coming to attack you, you say, "Honey, honey..."
How can honey become Jesus?
"Honey, honey...", it will not say,
"What is happening, my dear?"
Is that not what has happened to you?
People come with gun to attack you,
you say, "... Honey, honey..."
Honey will not say, "My dear,
what happened, in Jesus name?"
And they have attacked you already
before you called that name.
They have attacked you because the
Word has not become part of you.
Has the Word dominated us?
Is the Word living in us?
Jesus is building Himself in us,
making Himself a part of us.
The Word has not yet dominated you.
It has not yet dwelt in you.
You can have the knowledge of the Bible -
you read, memorize and use it to preach, teach, lecture
but living by it, it must dwell in you.
Don't forget those passages and Books given to you.
Take your time to read the
Book of Ephesians 3, from verse 17,
the Book of John 15; take reading from verse 7,
the Book of Acts 20; take reading from verse 32,
the Book of Colossians 3;
take your reading from verse 16.
You cannot build one up spiritually.
Because, today this is what is happening
all over today, everywhere.
Church has become an entertainment.
We cannot build people up spiritually
on the theory about the Book,
on the history or philosophy.
"Jesus is this. The mother is here. The father is this.
The Son is this. He was born in the manger..."
You cannot be built up spiritually on the history of the Book, the theory about the Book
or philosophy of the Book.
The Word must dominate, live in us.
Building can only come from the heart;
it is what comes from our heart that can build.
Don't forget at the beginning I said,
if I hold grudges, I should not be surprised
to see that the Bible is no longer real to me
when talking, reading, preaching.
See what is going on in churches today;
there is so much division - that is grudges.
This is why the Bible is no longer real to us,
because of so much division.
"This one is not good. That one is not good."
- fight everywhere in the churches.
The churches are no longer one.
This is why the Bible is no longer real to us.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are no longer one.
Fight.
Many of us are here today without the permission, because if you tried to collect permission,
they would not allow you to come.
Many are sitting at the back; each
time the camera is coming they dodge,
because they don't want their mentor to see them.
Each time the camera comes...
Some even put on very dark shade.
Each time camera comes they bow.
Instead of bowing to Jesus they bow to camera.
When it is mass prayer, instead of facing
on front, they turn back, "In Jesus name";
as if Holy Spirit is the one turning them.
... because you cannot bear the
consequence, after leaving here.
They will chase you out of your business,
your house - because they are your bread.
This is why the Bible is no longer real to us,
because there is division.
I want to leave you here.
I don't want you to have too much to think about.
I want you to have so much to meditate
about, not to think about.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you...
TT ROBERT BEGIER 24/06/2018
RV LIZZ NDUNG'U 30/08/2018